Guide to the Havelock Ellis Papers, 1931-1977.
Ellis, Havelock papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Havelock Ellis Papers, 1931-1977.
7773
Havelock, Ellis 1859-1939.
0.2 cubic feet.
Correspondence
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Documents related to the publishing of Havelock Ellis' "The Psychology of Sex" in the United States, including signed contracts, his copyright claim, and Francoise Lafitte-Cyon's 1966 renewal of the copyright claim.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Henry Havelock Ellis, born February 2, 1859, was a British physician and psychologist who wrote several influential works on sexuality. He died on July 8, 1939.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Documents related to the publishing of Havelock Ellis' "The Psychology of Sex" in the United States, including signed contracts, his copyright claim, Francoise Lafitte-Cyon's 1966 renewal of the copyright claim, Emerson Press correspondence with Dr. Allen Forbath who used Ellis' research in this book "Love and Marriage" (Liveright Press, 1939), a signed letter from Ellis to Emerson press dated February 11, 1939 mentioning his eightieth birthday and a request for circulars of "Psychology of Sex," several letters commenting on his failing health and death including an August 11, 1939 letter from Florence Rose, Secretary to Margaret Sanger (Folder 4), and reviews, royalty statements, estate filings, and correspondence regarding publication of subsequent editions. The collection's original folders contain descriptive information and have been retained in Folder 12.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Ellis, Havelock,1859-1939.; Ellis, Havelock, 1859-1939.
Subjects:
Sex (Psychology)
INFORMATION FOR USERS
NOTES
Collecting Program: Human Sexuality Collection.
CONTAINER LIST
- Psychology of Sex- Copyright, 1931-1966 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Photographs and Publicity, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Ray Long and Richard R. Smith, Inc., 1935 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Percy Elias- Emerson Books, Inc., 1935-1939 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Alex Forbath Correspondence, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Arthur Pell- Liveright Publishing Co. Ltd., Alex Forbath and "Love and Marriage", 1938 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Havelock Ellis- Deceased, 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Reprint Rights Sold, 1940-1977 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Estate of Havelock Ellis, 1940-1979 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Liveright- "Love and Marriage", 1943 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Permission Sold Or Granted, 1953-1978 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Folders that Came with the Collection, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 12)